Subway Sadie is a romance, comedy, drama film directed by Alfred Santell.
A New York fur saleswoman falls for a man she meets on the subway and must decide if she wants
to accept a much dreamed for work transfer to Paris, or stay and get married.
Sadie Hermann, played by Dorothy Mackaill.
Herb McCarthy, played by Jack Mulhall.
Taxicab Driver, played by Charles Murray.
Ethel, played by Peggy Shaw.
Fred Perry, played by Gaston Glass.
Brown, played by Bernard Randall.
Subway Sadie is a 1926 American silent comedy-drama
film directed by Alfred Santell.
Adapted from Mildred Cram's 1925 short story "Sadie of the Desert", the film focuses on a relationship between New York salesgirl Sadie
Hermann (Dorothy Mackaill) and subway guard Herb McCarthy (Jack Mulhall), who meet on the subway and become engaged.
However, after Sadie receives a promotion, she must
choose between her new job and marrying Herb.
The cast also includes Charles Murray, Peggy Shaw,
Gaston Glass, and Bernard Randall.
The film began production in May 1926.
Arthur Edeson served as cinematographer, shooting around
Central Park in areas like casinos and nightclubs.
Distributed by First National Pictures, the film
premiered in New York on September 12, 1926.
Many publications wrote positively of the film,
praising its acting and Santell's direction.
Today, it remains unknown whether a print of Subway Sadie has survived.
The tone is lighthearted and emotional.